

410.591.6249 ryan.hadfield@gmail.com Salt Lake City, Utah 84121

Portfolio: www.ryanhadfield.com **GitHub**: github.com/ryanhadfield

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-hadfield

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with an extensive background in sales, project management, marketing, and product development. Graduate of the University of Utah Coding Boot Camp with skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and MERN stack. Excited about collaborating with others, learning new technologies, and building something innovative. Looking forward to combining web engineering skills with years of experience and well-established passion for product, the outdoors, and a good eye for a trend.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+
- Applications: Github, Visual Studio Code, Heroku, Microsoft Office Suite, Asana, Slack, Zoom, Git Bash
- Tools: Bootstrap, NodeJS, MaterializeCSS, JQuery, MySql, Express, Handlebars, ReactJS, NoSql, MongoDB, Framer-Motion
- Skills: Brand Management, Product Design & Development, eCommerce Management, API, Project Management

PROJECTS

Best Snow | https://github.com/ryanhadfield/Best-Snow | https://ryanhadfield.github.io/Best-Snow

- A map-based web application that intuitively displays the best snowpack levels across the Western United States.
- Role: Team lead, Front-end development & UX/UI design.
- Tools: Javascript, JQuery, API, NodeJS, CanvasJS, Bing Maps, MomentJS
- Awards: Best UX/UI, Best use of tech

N-DEVR | https://aithub.com/ryanhadfield/N-DEVR | https://ndevr.herokuapp.com

- A full-stack web application powered by Strava that helps users plan their next big adventure.
- Role: Team Lead, Database creation, Front-end development, Logo design & UX/UI design
- Tools: Javascript, JQuery, NodeJS, CanvasJS, LeafletJS, Express, MySql
- Awards: Best UX/UI, Gold Medal

Swapify | https://github.com/ryanhadfield/SWAPIFY | https://swapify-us.herokuapp.com

- A full-stack React application that helps users swap unwanted items with neighbors and friends.
- Role: Team lead and Creator, Front-end development, Logo design & UX/UI design
- Tools: ReactJS, MongoDB, Firebase, OAuth2.0, MaterializeCSS, Framer-Motion
- Awards: Best UX/UI, Most Incredibly Cool Idea, Most likely to Monetize.

EXPERIENCE

Pro Purchase Program Manager, Liberty Mountain, 2013 - 2020, Salt Lake City, UT

- Managed the Influencer/Pro sales channel and eCommerce platform for an outdoor gear manufacturer and distributor representing over 900 brands and 30,000+ products in the outdoor segment.
- Generated double-digit sales growth YOY for 6 years and established a \$2M sales channel.
- Increased sales through targeted marketing, new customer acquisition, and increased brand offerings.
- Collaborated with marketing to develop targeted email campaigns, competitive e-commerce website features, and social media content.
- Introduced and implemented 3rd party pro purchase partnerships to increase overall sales and grow the influential customer base.
- Played an integral role in the deployment of new D2C eCommerce sites for the organization.
- Exhibited at industry trade shows as well as marketing events targeted toward B2B and D2C customers.

Procurement Coordinator, Black Diamond Equipment, 2011 - 2012, Salt Lake City, UT

- Managed the implementation and use of project management solutions to increase organization and efficiency of the supply chain department.
- Performed as a procurement manager and finished goods buyer for several product categories.
- Promoted and maintained relationships with vendor partners for new and carry over products and categories.
- Managed and instructed product reworks to turn affected products back into sellable inventory and complete the commercialization stage.
- Owned the product development cycle from SMS to the finalized commercialization stage.
- Coordinated the tracking of commodities, labor, and exchange rates for the seasonal carry-over cost negotiation processes.
- Reported to senior-level management on the company's global inventory positions and collaborated with sales to strategically manage sell-through.

International Development & Production Manager, Diamond Select Toys & Collectibles, LLC, 2005 - 2011, Timonium, MD

- Managed international product development, promotion, and manufacturing bringing over 200+ products to market.
- Acted as liaison with international factories, vendors, and representative groups.
- Worked closely with the company's Hong Kong consultants to establish deadlines, manage costs, and ensure product quality.
- Promoted and sourced new factories/vendors, developing new techniques and innovations for products.
- Built and maintained BOMs and tech packs for each project with our international vendors.
- Reviewed and tested samples from prototype to FEP stage of the product development cycle.
- Communicated scheduling, cost, or any other information which would benefit management.

Sales Specialist, Recreational Equipment Inc., Apr 2000 - Apr 2011, Timonium, MD

- Maintained a working knowledge of REI products and services and used this knowledge to sell products and services that specifically met the needs of B2C customers.
- Administered clinics on Mountaineering, Backpacking, Camping, Snowshoeing and Climbing to customers, fellow employees, and community groups.
- Built customer loyalty through the company's membership program, outlining the features and benefits to customers to promote enrollment.

Key Account Sales Manager, Diamond Comic Distributors, Inc, Nov 2001 - Nov 2005, Timonium, MD

- Managed detailed order processing and sales operations for 20+ national and international key accounts.
- Introduced the use of EDI fulfillment and compliance to grow sales and sell into mass market and big-box chains.
- Communicated with our inside and outside sales representatives weekly to ensure efficient and profitable business.
- Compiled, analyzed, and presented key account summaries to senior management as well as other departments within the company.

EDUCATION

University of Utah

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Towson University

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

UMBC

Major Focus: Premedical Research Technology